You win!
I wonder what it's like in
the Everlasting Stratum?
Well, it's an unconquered place of darkness
at the lowest level of this dungeon.
There's a big open area at the start.
Then a valley.
One so deep you can't see the bottom.
Past that, there are three straight paths.
And that's it. Really?
It gets even weirder.
Of the three, only the path that's
on the right has ever been bested.
A certain hunter walked down
that path for an entire year.
It seemed to stretch onward
in a straight line forever.
Until eventually he
encountered a dead end.
And that, they say, is why it's
called the Everlasting Stratum.
It feels like I could die of
boredom just thinking about it.
Pidgey, too.
That sounds awful.
He must have had an iron
will and super sensible
shoes to walk a dark
path for a whole year.
I hear it took the hunter another
year just to make it back home.
He never so much as saw a
plant, much less a monster.
He would have normally starved to death,
but it seems his blessing got him through.
Whoa, you think maybe that's why
Captain Kerioyl wants Boxo so bad?
It makes sense.
We know Sulream has the
blessing of transference,
but it only works if she's been there.
So they progress, warp back, and restock,
repeating the cycle over and over again
whenever they run out of food and stuff.
That sounds like a brutal existence.
If they had yours truly,
they'd be drowning in packaged food,
and I could store their
stuff in my coin lockers.
It doesn't sound amazing, but
we'll suck it up and try our best.
I bet even a year will fly by in no
time if we're together, you know?
That's so true!
I'll be happy as long as I'm with Foxo!
Foxo here will keep our bellies
nice and full, so no worries there!
Pity agrees.
It'll all work out.
I'm starting to get excited.
But what about wheels?
Guess we'll have to rustle up a
team of Unasusu to pull a wagon.
Too bad Kiko Yu and Botan on
a round to speed up our trip.
The time sink will be our
biggest sticking point.
Oh, snap!
Speaking of points, I pwned
that mid-ranked shark general.
I got honor and over a million points!
Ka-ching!
I have 2,370,000!
I'm so close to 3 mil I
can practically smell it!
Which means your boy, Boxo, is this close
to knowing the glories of rank three!
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box,
but inside, I've still got a human soul!
In this new world of wonders,
I travel to and fro on the back of
my super strong partner, Llamas!
The name's Boxo! Hello there!
That means yes, by the way!
I can't give...
This is mine, too You can't give...
...or I can give...
I can't give...
Look, look, look I can't
tell him the only thing!
Keep the effort of mini go
I can't give...
I can't give... I can't give...
I don't think... I don't know...
I can't give...
Don't sue me...
I don't want to...
Get it, take it.
I gather that on the world.
I know, so now!
You'll be there. Yeah, it's all!
I know, like you.
The light of the stars.
If you are here enough?
I want to dream.
That's what it is.
I love that you have.
I love you.
Master, I shall accompany
you on your journey.
It doesn't matter where you're going.
I would follow you off a cliff.
I will join your mission as well.
A long journey lends itself to
introspection, which feeds the soul.
Unrelated, but long treks are
also treacherous on footwear.
We have no choice but to bring a
mountain of spare shoes with us.
But worry not.
I will dispose of any worn-out pairs
once they're too odorless and filthy.
Anyway, we're going with Master Boxo.
That should give us an
overwhelming advantage in
our attempt to conquer
the Everlasting Stratum.
What could possibly go wrong?
You still can't afford to be careless.
Yes, yes.
Hey, something wrong, Heavy?
A thought, though I hate to say it.
I imagine the Netherlord
won't be in favor of our trip.
Surely not.
In fact, there's a strong chance he'll
attempt to sabotage us along the way.
Too true.
Director!
Sorry, sir,
but I just received word that Pinky
General Kylings has broken out of prison.
She escaped?
That goth, five-finger general we
nabbed in the Dark Forest Stratum.
Pretty sure she's one of
the Netherlord's baddies.
Did the guards survive?
All of those guards were put to sleep,
but thankfully they're
not in any mortal danger.
That's good.
Now tell me what happened.
We discovered they were sleeping when it
came time for the scheduled shift change.
Unfortunately, she had already vanished.
Her cell was completely empty.
A blade had sliced through her bars.
They were made of a special alloy that
was designed to block her blessing.
You're saying someone with a
flair for martial arts did it.
Yumite, is such a thing even possible?
Well, of course it's possible.
I could do the same thing
myself if I wanted to.
You're a scary woman.
Whoever broke her out is
immensely talented. Director!
There's trouble brewing.
A hunter returned to our village after
an expedition, bringing a warning.
There's a whole horde of monsters coming.
How many?
That's the thing.
He said there were at least 500.
Talk about deja vu.
The village is still recovering from
the last time this trope happened.
Coyowing's escape just got
slapped down the priority list.
Form change!
That's a horde all right, and
it's hornier than last time.
Yeah, it's not looking good.
Those three types would
normally be fighting each other,
but they're after us instead.
Blame the Netherlord.
I guess this means he's dead set against
us going to the Everlasting Stratum.
Thank you, Boxo.
Having you here in times of crisis
certainly makes things much easier.
Thanks for all the cool stuff, Boxo.
You're a lifesaver.
I love this towel.
We help each other very much.
It's good to hear you say that.
After all, we're currently housing a large
number of evacuees from other strata.
Your kindness will be rewarded later
when you get the coins you're owed.
I give you my word.
Hello there.
Now's a good time to
suck up on projectiles.
Grab some arrows and throwing knives.
We also offer weapon and armor repair.
Thanks to the stinky crisis we're
in, everything's free of charge.
Take what you need and
please don't hold back.
I see I'm not the only one hard at work.
That's so sweet of you
to hand out weapons.
It's pretty extravagant even
for you to not charge anything.
Simple logic.
To quote the timeless wisdom of my father,
sometimes the best gain is to lose.
Now's the perfect chance to
spend some good PR for our brand.
Fortunately, I was well-prepared and
already stocked up far in advance.
She's just saying that.
They obviously bought
up all those weapons.
Out of concern for us lowly villagers.
Yeah, I think so too.
Hello there!
They're still over a kilometer away.
Weird, they're not getting any closer?
Are they stalling?
Or amassing their forces
for one big attack?
I'm exhausted. Good morning.
Great, guard duty's over!
See you later, Boxo.
We're gonna go get some shut-eye now.
Try not to push yourself too hard.
Yes.
We're together, at least till tonight.
You're a trooper.
Please promise to take a break
should exhaustion overwhelm you.
Thank you very much.
I wonder when our fierce
foes will begin their march.
Do you think maybe
they're not going to come?
Perhaps we should get this party started.
But then we're toast if it
turns out to be a fiendish trap.
Should we continue waiting
or launch the first attack?
Or is there an even better option?
I'd like your unfiltered
opinions on the matter.
If you want a hot take, I got
one ready and waiting for ya!
Let's go pulverize some monsters!
But we're all here talking
about our feelings!
The Monster Horde is
getting bigger and badder!
If we choose to bring the fight to them,
we must prepare ourselves
for heavy casualties.
Hold up!
Instead of lots of us dying,
can't we wipe some of them
out with a small strike team?
Not dying is at least
worth a try. That said,
I think it would be most
effective to chip away at
their numbers by unleashing
some powerful ranged attacks.
Hmm, I know where this is going.
If you're in the market for
wholesale destruction magic,
I'd be more than happy to oblige.
Simmer down.
Try not to get carried away, Gramps.
Brilliant.
We'll prepare a wagon for the strike
team as well as the detachment of guards.
If things don't go our way, the team
will immediately retreat to safety.
By team, he means this grab
bag of named characters.
Be careful, and don't forget to come
running back if things go south.
Don't do anything crazy.
We'll be safe, I promise.
And we'll turn tail and run if
things get too dangerous out there.
Well, it'll win.
Who's that box?
Say, Gramps, don't you think we
should already be in range by now?
Right you are.
Director and Lamas, could you
please park us over there?
Hoxie, Shui, prepare to counterattack.
I'm ready and waiting.
Let's do this already.
La imps.
Need something, Boxo?
Oh, imp, ma 'i. Huh?
You want me to do what now?
Can you repeat that?
Oh, imp, ma 'i, off the air.
So you really want me to toss
you up and flip you around?
Meaning your bottom would be on top?
Yes, yes.
Now I'm locked and loaded.
I don't really get it, but
if you're sure about this...
All right, I hope you like
the wind in your eyes!
Now it's my turn!
Concrete foundation blocks ready!
Toss up with E.
Oh, so that's the reason
you're upside down.
Let's do this!
Did you see that? It worked!
Yes, again.
We'll make use of this
opportunity to retreat.
Long as stay up there.
Keep using whatever Boxo
gives you to keep them at bay.
All righty.
Pity, lighten the wagon.
As for Shui and Hoxie, feel
free to fire away. Sure thing.
It's time for
Plan B as unfair.
If I had to guess, I'd say
the monsters are probably.
Being controlled by a skull ring,
Which means they can only follow
simple orders like attack or retreat.
By leading the horde of monsters
past the ramparts again and
again will gradually cut their
forces down to a manageable number?
Our victory!
We should hunt down any remnants!
I'm going with you.
Taking on this many
crocodile fins won't be easy,
but our group should be able to handle it.
I see frogs in need of flambing.
Can't let you hog all the fun, can I?
Count me in!
Well then, perhaps you and I should do
something about those two snakes, eh, Gramps?
Shall we?
I'd prefer more of a
challenge, but it'll do.
Fighting alongside you two sure does
bring me back to the good old days.
We can lend you a hand.
Allow the four of us to take
care of the two-headed snake.
Of course.
In that case, we shall deal
with the crocodile fiends.
Please make sure to keep your
footwear safe from any harm.
Why would I expect anything else?
No matter what, I'll keep Boxo safe.
We'll help you take out
the crocodile fiends!
Hello there!
I'll make him pincushions.
You know, I could use a pair
of nice crocodile-skin boots.
Thanks so much, Betty.
Yeah, don't worry, I'll cover you.
Roaring strike!
And don't forget about us!
Has anyone spotted whoever is
commanding the monsters yet?
I haven't seen anything.
What about you, Boxo? Too bad!
It would seem this battle isn't over yet.
You can say that again, Gramps.
I suppose this means we were
their main target all along.
Yes, I do believe you're right.
Hold on a second.
Is it just me or is that the Stratum
Lord you defeated, Master Boxo? Or Ek?
Boxo, make sure you don't
get eaten this time, okay?
Did you have to bring that up?
Well, stop it here.
Take this!
Whoa, what did you do to it?
I've made it so that the Stratum Lord's
body is now several times heavier.
It's your turn, take it from here.
He knows gravity magic too?
Okay, leave it to us.
Get ready, today's the day I'll
finally surpass you, ma 'am.
If you manage it, I'll give
you my bow as a reward.
Alanis, throw me at his other leg.
Wait, what?
Really?
You want to be thrown?
Do it.
She was aiming for a different leg.
But hey, it turned out all right.
I suppose I should do my part, too.
Ha-chaa!
I can't hold it for much longer!
Should we do it?
Way to go, Lamas!
She knew exactly what I had
in mind next. Hello there.
Honestly, I'd rather you didn't fight.
But I know I've got to have
faith in my partner. Yes.
Right!
Up you go!
Time for a high-altitude form change!
Here comes the biggest
vending machine in Japan!
Equipped with concrete foundation
blocks for added weight.
Let's see how the Stratum Lord likes this!
Oh, wow, that was masterfully done.
Are you okay, Boxo?
Anything broken?
Oh, pepper, apple, apple.
That's a huge relief.
I was worried I might have thrown
you a little too high up. Right.
That should put a stop to the
Netherlord's plans for now.
Though it bugs me that Pinky
General Kyolings got away.
Anyway, we ought to
celebrate this victory.
Cheers!
I drink way too much.
Voxo, please give me something
that'll make me feel better.
Can I get one of those as well? Yes, yes.
You mean sports drinks.
Looks like you got wiped out.
Calm now.
You all should learn to really
hold your liquor better.
Goodness.
Hang in there.
I hope you're all back on your feet soon.
We'll be open today.
Come visit us, all right?
How are you okay?
I remember you drank several
times more than we did.
That's what makes her a pro.
Now that I've defeated an eight-legged
crocodile stratum lord, my point total is...
3,240,000!
I actually gathered up
over 3 million points!
And now that I've finally cleared
that milestone, you guessed it.
Rank 3 is within my reach at last!
It won't be just a dream anymore!
That day, I was reincarnated in
another world as a vending machine.
And since then,
I've used my vast vending machine
knowledge to turn into different models.
I know Lamas was worried about me,
but ever since I beat that
eight-legged crocodile
to reach rank 2 and saw
rank 3 in my function list,
I couldn't help but be
curious about what it meant.
Now it's finally within reach!
With this many points saved up,
I could totally spend them all
to learn three new blessings.
But no, I'm going to increase
my rank no matter what.
I have to keep growing in order to help my
friends face whatever
challenges come our way.
I am definitely not letting my vending
machine obsession take control here.
No Suori.
You can believe me on that.
I am making this choice
for my friends, okay?
Um, so maybe there's a teensy
part of it that's for me too?
Well, anyway, there's no time
like the present for that rank up.
I'm ready to invest those three
million points I've been saving up.
Yeah, boy!
Your painting machine rank has
increased from two to three.
I can feel a new power
coursing through my metal body.
So this is what rank three is all about.
Let's see here.
I haven't scrolled through
my mental cursor in a while.
The effective range of blessings
and telekinesis has been doubled.
Oh that's a nice quality of life change.
Things like my barrier and telekinesis
get more useful the more range they have.
Time allowed to change
form into other vending
machines increases from
two hours to four hours.
Oh yes please.
There have been things I couldn't
do because of the time limit.
So doubling it gives me more
room to dream more vending
machines and functions are
now available for selection.
It is now possible for you to transform
into any vending machine that exists
or has ever existed in the past including
never purchased never used models.
Say what you mean.
Now I can choose from vending
machines from foreign countries
and even older models that
used to be around but have been
discontinued.
This is amazing.
I could pick something
from the UK or or that
one from the US.
I'm getting really fired up. Let me see.
Wow, there are even
throwback models in here.
I'm about to go crazy
from sheer joy. Hold on.
Does this mean I could choose that one?
If that's possible, it would make
conquering the everlasting stratum a cinch.
Let's check it out.
Man, I haven't been this
hyped in a long time.
When I reached rank two,
the new functions I got were additional
self-service models and optional add-ons.
Those concrete slabs I've been using so
much lately were part of that package so i
wonder what's going to get added now that
i'm ranked three the possibilities boggle
the mind i spent the rest of the night
pouring over the new vending machines and
goods i had at my disposal and at no point
did i even start to feel bored sweet sweet
Oh
don't want to say anything,
but I don't want to say anything.
I'm waiting for you to be in the kingdom.
Goodbye yeah you're
right it's not like we're
marching to our deaths agreed
it's just going to be a
quick one or two year
journey no point in getting
all mopey about it yay me
and boxo constantly together
it's a dream i'm glad to
get the chance to go on
an adventure with master
boxo with this group i'm
sure we won't get bored
even if this takes years to
complete right time to
activate the transfer circle
I see.
So this is the everlasting stratum.
I look forward to serving you again.
Thank you.